Dr. Helena F. Miller Collection, 1943-1945 mss.2.01.miller
Eastern Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Helena F. Miller Collection
1943-1945
Eastern Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Miller, Helena, Dr., Dean of Women
mss.2.01.miller
0.5 Linear Feet
Dr. Helena F. Miller taught English and served as Dean of Students from 1933-1946 at the Willimantic State Normal School (1933-1938)/Willimantic State Teacher's College (1938-1959) which is now Eastern Connecticut State University. This collection includes correspondence from her students during World War II and a collection of the newsletter "The Dean's Den".
Related Collections
The University Archives has a substantial collection of university archives material and also houses the Connecticut Studies Collection. For more detailed information on these collections please contact a staff member for more information.
Scope and Cotent Note
During World War II, Dr. Helena Miller, Dean of Women at the Willimantic State Teachers College, sent copies of a school publication entitled The Dean's Den to a number of students from the college who were serving their country. Many of the young people responded to Dr. Miller, to express their great appreciation for her efforts to keep them in touch with home as well as to keep her abreast of their wartime experiences. These correspondences cover an approximate 3 year period - 1943 through 1945. While some of these students were graduates of the college, a number of them left prior to graduation with the intent that they would resume their education on their return from the war.
Copyright
Permission to publish from these papers must be obtained in writing from both the Eastern Connecticut State University Archives & Special Collections and the owner(s) of the copyright.
Arrangement
Correspondence from students was filed first alphabetically by author's last name and by date. Newsletters "From the Dean's Den" are arranged in chronological order.
Eastern Connecticut State University; Willimantic State Teachers College; World War, 1939-1945.; Miller, Helena, Dr., Dean of Women
- Series I - Incoming Correspondence, 1943-1945; 0 Linear Feet
  - Miller, Dr. Helena, 1943-1945
  - Application for retirement, 1945; application form
  - Backus, Charles W., March 12, 1945; letter
  - Belanger, G. N., January 14, 1944; letter
  - Belanger, G. N., 26 January 1944; letter
  - Bergeron, George, 17 August 1943; letter
  - Bergeron, George, 1 October 1943; letter
  - Constagna, Joseph P., 5 April 1944; V mail
  - Congdon, Richard H., 29 September 1943; 0 Linear Feet letter
  - Congdon, Richard H., 8 April 1944; letter
  - DeGange, Joseph, 1 September 1943; letter
  - DeGange, Joseph, 1 February 1944; V mail
  - Dickson, Ernest E., 8 November 1943; letter
  - Dickson, Ernest E., 2 December 1943; letter
  - Dickson, Ernest E., 12 February 1944; letter
  - Dickson, Ernest E., 12 February 1945; letter
  - Fontaine, Arthur R., 16 August 1943; letter
  - Fontaine, Arthur R., 7 January 1944; letter
  - Fontaine, Arthur R., 21 January 1944; letter
  - Fontaine, Arthur R., 8 March 1944; letter
  - Fontaine, Arthur R., 17 April 1944; letter
  - Goodrich, Joseph L., 2 November 1943; letter
  - Goodrich, Joseph L., 7 October 1944; letter
  - Goodrich, Joseph L., 30 December 1944; letter
  - Holmes, Russell B., 4 November 1943; letter
  - Houle, Raymond, 22 August 1943; letter
  - Houle, Raymond, 4 September 1943; letter
  - Houle, Raymond, 8 October 1943; letter
  - Houle, Raymond, 30 November 1943; letter
  - Houle, Raymond, 25 March 1944; V mail
  - Houle, Raymond, 16 April 1944; letter
  - Irlandi, James, 26 July 1943; postcard
  - Irlandi, James, [1943]; V postcard
  - Irlandi, James, 23 September 1943; postcard
  - Irlandi, James, 7 January 1944; letter
  - Irlandi, James, 20 January 1944; letter
  - Irlandi, James, 7 March 1944; letter
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 6 August 1943; letter
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 25 September 1943; letter
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 12 February 1944; postcard
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 26 February 1944; letter
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 7 April 1944; letter
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 30 April 1944; postcard
  - Israel, Jay Burton, 20 February 1945; letter
  - Johnson, Kenneth F., 12 October 1943; letter
  - Jones, Ruth, 18 August 1943; letter
  - Jones, Ruth, 17 November 1943; letter
  - Jones, Ruth, 28 March 1944; letter
  - Leader, Jacob, 9 December 1944; V mail
  - Maynard, William, 15 November [1943]; postcard
  - Maynard, William, 29 November 1943; letter
  - Maynard, William, 21 December 1943; postcard
  - Ottenheimer, Edward J., 25 February 1944; letter
  - Petrus, John, 26 September 1943; letter
  - Petrus, John, 12 March 1945; V mail
  - Ready, John, 2 November 1943; V mail
  - Ready, John, 7 December 1943; letter
  - Ready, John, 6 January 1944; V mail
  - Ready, John, 3 February 1944; V mail
  - Ready, John, 21 Feburay 1944; V mail
  - Schepart, Howard, 17 August 1943; letter
  - Schepart, Howard, 21 January 1944; V mail
  - Scranton, Robert, 9 August 1943; letter
  - Scranton, Robert, 31 January 1944; V mail
  - Selavka, Jack, 21 September 1943; letter
  - Selavka, Jack, 30 December 1943; letter
  - Selavka, Jack, 15 January 1944; letter
  - Selavka, Jack, 25 January 1944; letter
  - Solnick, Martin G., 28 December 1943; letter
  - Timmins, J. W., 28 October 1943; newsletter "The Sergeants Locker Somewherin, Alaska"
  - Timmins, J. W., 7 March 1944; card
  - Weeks, Ernest, 27 October 1944; letter
  - Wibberly, Janette, 5 April 1945; letter
- Series II - Dean's Den Newsletters, 1943-1945; 0 Linear Feet
  - From the Dean's Den, September 1943; 0.001 Linear Feet newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, October 1943; 0.001 Linear Feet newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, November 1943; 0.001 Linear Feet newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, Dec 1943/Jan 1944; 0.001 Linear Feet newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, February 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, March 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, April-May 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, June 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, September 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, October 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, Nov-Dec 1944; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, January 1945; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, 14 February 1945; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, March 1945; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, April 1945; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, May 1945; newsletter
  - From the Dean's Den, June 1945; newsletter